RAPHAEL AKO-MENSAH

SENIOR DESKTOP SUPPORT ENGINEER | WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

I am an all-round tech enthusiast with over seven years experience, focused on providing solutions to existing problems with the use of programming. I come from a tech support background, where my programming skills allow me to contribute to production processes and improve productivity for myself and my team.

Furthermore, as a freelance full stack web developer, I use technologies such as React, HTML5, CSS3, Python, APIs, SQL.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR EUX DESKTOP SUPPORT ENGINEER

ASOS (Client site via CDW)

April 2019 - Present

- Developing scripts (bash/PowerShell/Python) to automate tasks for different departments' operational concerns e.g.:
 - Bulk user creation script for service desk (Powershell)
 - Bash file transfer script for studios As model photos are taken, they are automatically moved to a shared network folder, so shoot editors can receive them automatically and improve workflow
 - Bash scripts to monitor software versions through JAMF and report regularly
- Supporting development teams with the use of tools such as:
 - Docker
 - MS SQL Server SSMS
 - Azure
 - GIT
 - Xcode

FREELANCE

JFM CONSULT -2021

Life Coach Consultancy Website jfmconsult.co.uk

- Django (Python)
- Twilio Sendgrid
- jQuery, Bootstrap
- Cloudflare
- SEO Optimized

ONLINE WATCH STORE

Retail Website

Offline - source files available

- Flask (Python)
- · Bootstrap, jQuery
- HTML, CSS, JS
- SQL Backend

ISPY SECURITY -2020

CCTV Installation Business Website ax99.github.io/iSpy-Security-Website/

- Bootstrap, jQuery
- HTML, CSS, JS

ECOMMERCE TEMPLATE - 2021

Template for an ecommerce website. Under construction github.com/AX99/Ecommerce-Store

- Python (Django)
- Shopping cart (AJAX)
- TailwindCSS
- Product database Admin panel

ONSITE ENGINEER

CDW

April 2019 - Present

- An IT Engineer delivering On-Site services for clients.
- Providing technical support for the End User Technology environment involving desktop computing and corporate IT services within the IT Service delivery team.
- Capable of working independently and remotely on a wide range of products and technologies.
- Qualifications:
 - M207031 Administering System Center Configuration Manager
 - JAMF Certified Associate JAMF Pro V10

DESKTOP ENGINEER | JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Lastminute.com Group July 2017 - April 2019

- A Technical Support Engineer part of a team providing remote and desktop support for incidents escalated by first/second line helpdesk within the UK, German, Spanish, Italian, Swiss, India, Polish and outsourced offices.
- Six months spent in Chiasso Switzerland as a junior software developer for LMGroup Jetcost, Rumbo, Volagratis & Bravofly.
- Creating digital in-house content using Photoshop. i.e. splash screens for video conferences and assets for web apps
- Working with the in-house development team during 6 month Erasmus programme in head office:
 - Creating, developing and maintaining web applications (HTML, CSS, JS)
 - Debugging and optimizing web apps
 - Contributing to the production process (meetings, code reviews, tasks estimation)
 - Implementing best practice concepts and testing (TDD)
 - Maintaining code for enterprise desktop software applications (Python)
- System/User management using G Suite (GAM scripting), Active Directory (Powershell scripting)

WEB AUTOMATION APP

Script that opens ELLC Choice Homes Website, logs user in and displays properties available to bid on.

github.com/AX99/ELLC-automation-tool

- Python
- Selenium

EDUCATION

2012 - 2013

KINGSTON UNIVERSITY

Mathematics & Computing (Foundation year)

2009 - 2011

HAVERING 6TH FORM

Mathematics, Economics, ICT (A Levels)

2004 - 2009

TOM HOOD COLLEGE

Mathematics (A*), English (BC), Science (BBB), IT (BB), French (B), Geography (C) (GCSEs)



07415 426 781



rapha.mensah@gmail.com



London/Remote



github.com/AX99